Robert Roberts

123 Third Street, Newark, NJ 07777 r. roberts @ emaiI. com (111) 222-3333

PROFILE

Punctual and courteous professional with a strong knowledge base of commercial and residential HVAC systems. Over seven years' experience of both problem-solving on a solo basis and working as part of a team. Excellent at customer relations, including providing accurate estimates and clear communication. Good at troubleshooting malfunctioning HVAC components.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

HVAC Technician

HVAC Professional Services, Newark, NJ | November 2015 - Present

- Troubleshoot heating and cooling units in commercial buildings and homes
- Develop and recommend solutions to clients, keeping budgetary and schedule considerations in mind
- Perform repairs or install new equipment as appropriate
- Train junior employees on techniques and safety best practices and provide oversight during projects
- Coordinate the preventative maintenance plans of 35 residential customers and five commercial clients

Junior HVAC Technician

ABC A/C Services, New Brunswick, NJ | July 2013 - October 2015

- Responded to calls from residential customers, diagnosing and rectifying problems
- Completed company's commercial HVAC program, then accompanied senior employees on commercial jobs
- Assisted supervisors by compiling maintenance logs for repeat customers
- Assessed and reported on the company's part and tool supplies

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in HVAC Engineering

New Brunswick Technical Institute, New Brunswick, NJ September 2009 - June 2013

KEY SKILLS

- · Customer interactions
- Identifying HVAC problems and implementing solutions
- Providing cost-effective options
- Safe use of power tools
- Code and regulation compliance

CERTIFICATIONS

 HVAC Excellence Certificate, Organization for HVAC Professionalism, 2019